Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about sports and outdoor activities.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊的是运动和户外活动。
That's right.
没错。
We are taking a look at a lot of different adventure sports.
我们正在介绍很多不同的冒险运动。
So they're not just regular sports like tennis or soccer.
所以它们不是像网球或足球那样的普通运动。
These are more dangerous sports.
这些是更危险的运动。
That's right.
没错。
So adventure sports is the topic.
所以冒险运动就是今天的主题。
This is intermediate level.
这是中级课程。
Let's check out the dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
我们先来听一段对话，一会儿再回来。
Welcome to Adventure Tours.
欢迎来到冒险之旅旅行社。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
I want to book a tour with Adventure Sports.
我想在冒险运动公司预订一次旅行。
Excellent.
太好了。
Our company has more than 10 years of experience in the adventure tourism and sports field.
我们公司在冒险旅游和运动领域有超过十年的经验。
Let me show you some options.
让我给您看一些选择。
This is our most popular choice.
这是最受欢迎的项目。
Our river guides will take you on a white water rafting trip followed by a ride in a
我们的河流向导会带您进行白水漂流之旅，随后乘坐
hot air balloon.
热气球。
I don't really think I'm ready to throw myself down a river full of jagged rocks in a rubber
我真不觉得自己准备好要跳进一条满是尖石头的河里，坐在橡皮
boat or go up in the air in a wicker basket held up by an oversized balloon.
船上，或者坐进一个由超大号气球吊着的柳条篮子里飞上天。
What else do you have?
你还有什么别的选择？
Well, in that case, we can take you hang gliding with one of our experienced instructors.
嗯，这样的话，我们可以让你和一位经验丰富的教练一起玩滑翔翼。
It's the closest you can get to flying.
这是最接近飞行的体验了。
What?
什么？
You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
你是说把自己绑在一个脆弱的风筝上？
No thank you.
不了，谢谢。
Next.
下一个。
Okay.
好的。
Well, why don't you tell me a little bit more about what you would like?
嗯，那你不如多跟我说说你想玩什么？
We have everything from mountain biking to rock climbing to street luge.
我们从山地自行车到攀岩再到街头雪橇，什么都有。
I'm thinking something exciting but safer.
我在想一些刺激但更安全的活动。
I have the perfect option.
我有个完美的选择。
This package will take you on a hiking trip through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards
这个套餐会带你去喜马拉雅山徒步三天，之后
there's a dog sledding journey.
还有一段狗拉雪橇之旅。
That's more like it.
这还差不多。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously this tour agency or tour operator has a lot of different options.
所以很明显，这家旅行社或旅游运营商有很多不同的选择。
A lot of them exciting so why don't we take a look at some of those on Language Takeaway.
其中很多都很刺激，那我们不如在“语言要点”环节看看其中一些。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the first one has to do with water.
第一个词跟水有关。
This is called white water rafting.
这叫做激流漂流。
That's right.
没错。
So white water rafting.
所以是激流漂流。
Now rafting means that you go in a raft.
漂流的意思是你乘坐一艘筏子。
That's right.
没错。
It's a special kind of boat, not a wooden boat, not like a big boat you see in the ocean.
这是一种特殊的船，不是木船，也不是你在海里看到的那种大船。
This is a special boat for rivers maybe.
这可能是专门用于河流的船。
That's right.
没错。
It's an inflatable rubber boat.
它是一种充气橡皮船。
So he also described it as a rubber boat.
所以他也把它描述为橡皮船。
Okay, rubber is the material it's made out of.
好的，橡胶是它制成的材料。
That's right.
没错。
So you go in this boat in a river and it's called white water because it has rapids.
所以你乘这艘船在河里，它被称为“白水”是因为有急流。
So the river is moving very quickly and you can see that it's a little bit dangerous to
所以河水流动得非常快，你可以看到在这样的河里游泳有点危险。
go swimming in a river like this.
在这样的河里游泳有点危险。
That's right.
没错。
So the water goes really fast or when it hits some rocks, the color changes from being blue
所以水流得非常快，或者当它撞击岩石时，颜色从蓝色或棕色变成白色，这就是为什么它叫激流漂流。
or brown to white and that's why it's white water rafting.
It's very, very scary and very dangerous.
这非常非常吓人，而且很危险。
That's right, but very exciting.
没错，但也很刺激。
So that's considered an adventure sport.
所以那被认为是一项极限运动。
And then the trip was followed by a ride in a hot air balloon.
然后那次旅行之后还乘坐了热气球。
Well everyone's seen balloons before.
嗯，大家都见过气球。
Sometimes we give children balloons at the fair or maybe for their birthday.
有时候我们在游乐场或生日时给孩子们气球。
Balloons are basically rubber filled with air.
气球基本上就是充满空气的橡胶。
But a hot air balloon is a very special kind of mode of transportation actually.
但热气球实际上是一种非常特殊的交通工具。
You can travel in a hot air balloon.
你可以乘坐热气球旅行。
That's right.
没错。
It's a big, big balloon that has a basket under it and the person actually described
那是一个很大的气球，下面挂着一个篮子，那个人实际上描述
it as a wicker basket.
它是一个柳条篮。
A wicker is the material that's used in the basket, right?
柳条是篮子用的材料，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
It's not furniture like wicker chairs.
它不像柳条家具那样。
It's just a way to basically make furniture out of this kind of bark or natural material.
它只是用这种树皮或天然材料制作家具的一种方式。
So a hot air balloon is a very big balloon and it's filled with hot air, usually by some
所以热气球是一个很大的气球，里面充满热空气，通常由下面
sort of fire that's under it.
某种火焰加热。
And because it's filled with hot air, it goes up in the air and as you say, you can use
因为充满热空气，它会升到空中，就像你说的，你可以用它
it as transportation, maybe to go very long distances carried by the wind because there's
作为交通工具，也许可以随风飞行很远的距离，因为那里有
no real way of giving a direction or just for fun.
没有真正的方向指示，或者只是为了好玩。
That's right.
没错。
It's another dangerous but less dangerous kind of sport.
这是另一种危险但相对不那么危险的运动。
But after that, we actually have one that I think you have some experience with.
但之后，我们实际上有一个我认为你有些经验的项目。
It's called hang gliding.
它叫悬挂式滑翔。
That's right.
没错。
Hang gliding is another type of sport and also a type of flying sport and basically
悬挂式滑翔是另一种运动，也是一种飞行运动，基本上
you get on a hang glider.
你登上一个悬挂式滑翔机。
Okay.
好的。
So if you've seen this before, you'll know that it looks like someone is wearing wings.
如果你以前见过这个，你会知道它看起来像有人穿着翅膀。
That's right.
没错。
It's a big kite that you wear.
它是一个你穿在身上的大风筝。
It's a big kite.
它是一个大风筝。
It kind of looks like a triangle, like a kite.
它看起来有点像三角形，像风筝。
And you fly in it.
你在里面飞行。
So it has no motor.
所以它没有发动机。
It has not like the hot air balloon, it has no fire.
它不像热气球，没有火。
So you just basically glide.
所以你基本上只是滑翔。
You just sail through the air, the atmosphere.
你只是在空中、大气中航行。
Sounds very peaceful.
听起来很平静。
It is.
是的。
But they say that you should go with an instructor.
但人们说你应该和教练一起去。
So what kind of instructor does this tour company offer?
那么这家旅游公司提供什么样的教练呢？
That's right.
没错。
So our operator talked about taking you on a hang glider trip with one of our experienced
所以我们的操作员谈到带你去悬挂式滑翔旅行，由我们经验丰富的
instructors.
教练陪同。
So experienced is the key word here.
所以“经验丰富”是这里的关键词。
You want someone who has done this many times before, someone who knows what they are doing.
你想要一个以前做过很多次的人，一个知道自己在做什么的人。
That's right.
没错。
So an experienced instructor is a person that has, as you say, a lot of experience or is
所以经验丰富的教练就是像你说的，有很多经验的人，或者
a professional.
是专业人士。
So that's an experienced instructor.
那就是经验丰富的教练。
Right.
对。
You could even say, you know, I want to take flying lessons with an experienced pilot.
你甚至可以说，你知道，我想跟一位经验丰富的飞行员上飞行课。
Right.
对。
Or you can even talk about maybe a chef.
或者你甚至可以谈论一位厨师。
He is a very experienced chef.
他是一位经验丰富的厨师。
He's been a chef for a long time.
他当厨师很久了。
That's right.
没错。
So hang gliding.
所以是悬挂式滑翔。
And our final sport, very exciting as well.
还有我们最后一项运动，也非常刺激。
We are going dog sledding.
我们要去狗拉雪橇。
Okay.
好的。
So this is basically a winter sport or a sport that you do in snowy places.
所以这基本上是一项冬季运动，或者是在雪地进行的运动。
You stand or sit on a sled and a team of dogs, so that means many dogs, pull you across the
你站在或坐在雪橇上，一队狗，意思是很多狗，拉着你穿过
snow.
雪地。
That's right.
没错。
So you go on a sled, which is basically usually made out of plastic or wood, and this is to
所以你上雪橇，雪橇通常由塑料或木头制成，这是为了
go on top of the snow.
在雪上行驶。
And as you say, a team of dogs pull you.
正如你所说，一队狗拉着你。
I think you can see this in movies.
我想你可以在电影里看到这个。
This is kind of like the mode of transportation in places where there are no roads, there
这有点像在没有道路的地方的交通方式，那里
are no other ways of getting places that you just get pulled by dogs.
没有其他方式到达目的地，只能由狗拉着。
Like Alaska or the Arctic Circle, somewhere very, very far north.
比如阿拉斯加或北极圈，非常非常靠北的地方。
Exactly.
正是。
So a lot of great adventure sports.
所以有很多很棒的冒险运动。
Very exciting.
非常刺激。
I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue again.
我想是时候再听一遍对话了。
And we'll be back in a bit with Language Takeaway Part 2.
我们稍后会回来进行语言要点第二部分。
Welcome to Adventure Tours.
欢迎来到冒险之旅旅行社。
How may I help you?
我能为您效劳吗？
I want to book a tour with Adventure Sports.
我想预订一次冒险运动之旅。
Excellent.
太好了。
Our company has more than 10 years of experience in the adventure, tourism, and sports field.
我们公司在冒险、旅游和运动领域有超过10年的经验。
Let me show you some options.
让我给您看一些选择。
This is our most popular choice.
这是最受欢迎的选择。
Our river guides will take you on a whitewater rafting trip followed by a ride in a hot air
我们的河流导游会带您进行激流漂流，然后乘坐热
balloon.
气球。
I don't really think I'm ready to throw myself down a river full of jagged rocks in a rubber
我真的不认为自己准备好把自己扔进满是锯齿状岩石的河里，坐在橡皮
boat or go up in the air in a wicker basket held up by an oversized balloon.
船上，或者被一个超大号气球吊着的柳条篮子里升到空中。
What else do you have?
你们还有什么别的吗？
Well, in that case, we can take you hang gliding with one of our experienced instructors.
嗯，那样的话，我们可以带您和一位经验丰富的教练一起进行悬挂式滑翔。
It's the closest you can get to flying.
这是最接近飞行的体验。
What?
什么？
You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
你是说把自己绑在一个脆弱的风筝上？
No thank you.
不了，谢谢。
Next?
下一个呢？
Mm, OK.
嗯，好吧。
Well, why don't you tell me a little bit more about what you would like?
嗯，您为什么不告诉我更多您想要什么呢？
We have everything from mountain biking to rock climbing to street luge.
我们什么都有，从山地自行车到攀岩再到街头雪橇。
I'm thinking something exciting but safer.
我在想一些刺激但更安全的活动。
I have the perfect option.
我有个完美的选择。
This package will take you on a hiking trip through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards
这个套餐会带你进行为期三天的喜马拉雅山徒步旅行，之后
there's a dog sledding journey.
还有一段狗拉雪橇之旅。
That's more like it.
这才像话。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at three quick adjectives that we saw in this dialogue
现在我们要看看这段对话中出现的三个快速形容词
on Language Takeaway Part 2.
在“语言小贴士”第二部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
This first adjective is something I'm not a fan of.
第一个形容词是我个人不太喜欢的。
Let me just say if you ever go rafting and you see rocks, you want to avoid or you want
我只想说，如果你去漂流时看到岩石，你要避开或远离
to stay away from jagged rocks.
那些锯齿状的岩石。
That's right.
没错。
So the adjective jagged refers to maybe sharp or they can cut you, right?
所以形容词“jagged”指的是可能锋利或会割伤你的东西，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So something that is jagged is not smooth.
所以“jagged”的东西是不光滑的。
It's the opposite of smooth.
它是“光滑”的反义词。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you've seen some rocks that are very pointy or that have things that can easily
所以你可能见过一些非常尖的岩石，或者有容易
hurt you or cut you.
伤到你或割伤你的东西。
Those are jagged rocks.
那些就是锯齿状的岩石。
Broken glass can have jagged edges and that means you want to avoid touching it because
碎玻璃可能有锯齿状的边缘，这意味着你要避免触摸它，因为
it can hurt you.
它会伤到你。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So jagged is a way of describing something that's maybe sharp, pointy or very dangerous
所以“jagged”是用来描述可能锋利、尖锐或非常危险
that can cut you.
且能割伤你的东西。
And then moving on, when we were talking about the hot air balloon, this person very cleverly
然后继续，当我们谈论热气球时，这个人很聪明地
said that he doesn't want to go up in the air in a basket held by an oversized balloon.
说他不想坐在一个由超大号气球吊着的篮子里升到空中。
Okay, so he's exaggerating.
好吧，所以他是在夸张。
Like you said, he's being clever or silly.
就像你说的，他是在耍聪明或犯傻。
He's just afraid of the balloon.
他只是害怕气球。
But basically he's saying an oversized balloon is a very, very, very big or unnaturally big
但基本上，他说“oversized balloon”是一个非常、非常、非常大或异常大的
balloon.
气球。
Right.
对。
So bigger than normal.
所以比正常的大。
So an oversized balloon would be a balloon that's bigger than normal.
所以“oversized balloon”就是比正常大的气球。
Or maybe I've seen an oversized...
或者我见过超大号的……
In the early 1990s, I remember a clothing trend, a lot of people like to wear oversized
在1990年代初期，我记得有一种服装潮流，很多人喜欢穿超大号的
t-shirts.
T恤。
That's right.
没错。
So t-shirts that were way too big for you or maybe unnaturally big, those would be oversized
所以那些对你来说太大或异常大的T恤，就是超大号
t-shirts.
T恤。
Like XXXL.
比如XXXL。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right.
好了。
And our final adjective when he was talking about hang gliding, he said that he's not
最后一个形容词，当他谈论滑翔伞时，他说他还没准备好
ready to go up in the air strapped to a flimsy kite.
被绑在一个脆弱的风筝上飞到空中。
Okay, so the key word here is flimsy.
好吧，这里的关键词是“flimsy”。
We already talked about a kite.
我们已经讨论过风筝了。
It's something that flies in the air.
它是能在空中飞的东西。
But something that's flimsy is not very stable or sturdy.
但“flimsy”的东西不太稳定或坚固。
That's right.
没错。
So it doesn't seem like it's very solid.
所以它看起来不太结实。
So if you have a kite...
所以如果你有一个风筝……
So a normal airplane is very sturdy, but a paper airplane is very flimsy.
正常的飞机很坚固，但纸飞机很脆弱。
It's thin, it moves around a lot.
它很薄，容易晃动。
You can't control it.
你控制不了它。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So it's not very solid.
所以它不太结实。
It's not very, as you said, sturdy.
就像你说的，不太坚固。
It doesn't really seem like it can stay up in the air for very long.
它看起来不能在空中停留很久。
And it definitely can't support someone's weight.
而且肯定支撑不了人的重量。
That's right.
没错。
So you can even have a flimsy chair.
所以你甚至可以有脆弱的椅子。
Maybe the chair is a little bit loose or it doesn't seem like it's very strong.
也许椅子有点松，或者看起来不太结实。
It feels like it might break.
感觉可能会坏掉。
That's right.
没错。
So flimsy.
所以“flimsy”。
That's the adjective there, flimsy.
这就是那个形容词，“flimsy”。
So that's all the adjectives we have for you today.
这就是我们今天为你准备的所有形容词。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue quickly one last time and we'll be back to talk a
我们最后快速听一遍对话，然后回来再聊
little bit more.
一点。
Welcome to Adventure Tours.
欢迎来到冒险之旅旅行社。
How may I help you?
我能为您效劳吗？
I want to book a tour with Adventure Sports.
我想预订一个冒险运动的旅行团。
Excellent!
太好了！
Our company has more than 10 years of experience in the adventure, tourism, and sports field.
我们公司在冒险、旅游和运动领域有超过10年的经验。
Let me show you some options.
让我给您看一些选择。
This is our most popular choice.
这是最受欢迎的选择。
Our river guides will take you on a white water rafting trip followed by a ride in a
我们的河流导游会带您进行白水漂流之旅，之后乘坐
hot air balloon.
热气球。
I don't really think I'm ready to throw myself down a river full of jagged rocks in a rubber
我真不觉得自己准备好把自己扔进一条满是尖石头的河里，坐在一个橡皮
boat or go up in the air in a wicker basket held up by an oversized balloon.
船上，或者坐在一个由超大号气球撑起的柳条篮子里升到空中。
What else do you have?
你还有什么别的选择？
Well, in that case, we can take you hang gliding with one of our experienced instructors.
嗯，那样的话，我们可以让你和一位经验丰富的教练一起玩滑翔伞。
It's the closest you can get to flying.
这是最接近飞行的体验了。
What?
什么？
You mean strap myself to a flimsy kite?
你是说把自己绑在一个脆弱的风筝上？
No thank you.
不了，谢谢。
Next?
下一个？
Okay.
好吧。
Well, why don't you tell me a little bit more about what you would like?
嗯，那你不如多跟我说说你想要什么？
We have everything from mountain biking to rock climbing to street luge.
我们从山地自行车到攀岩再到街头雪橇，什么都有。
I'm thinking something exciting but safer.
我在想一些刺激但更安全的活动。
I have the perfect option.
我有个完美的选择。
This package will take you on a hiking trip through the Himalayas for three days and afterwards
这个套餐会带你去喜马拉雅山徒步三天，之后
there's a dog sledding journey.
还有一次狗拉雪橇之旅。
That's more like it.
这还差不多。
Okay so Marco, I know this is one of your favorite areas, Adventure Sports.
好的，马可，我知道这是你最喜欢的领域之一——冒险运动。
You're a lot more daring than I am because I wouldn't do many of these things but what
你比我大胆多了，因为我不会做这些事中的很多，但你
have you done?
做过哪些？
I've actually haven't been in a hot air balloon.
我其实没坐过热气球。
I don't really think that's very exciting.
我真不觉得那有多刺激。
It does seem kind of boring.
看起来确实有点无聊。
Yeah, you don't really go very fast.
是啊，速度也不快。
And I've never done a street luge which is an interesting sport although it is pretty
我也没玩过街头雪橇，那是一项有趣的运动，虽然挺
dangerous.
危险的。
It's basically, you're kind of riding on a type of skateboard, right?
基本上，就是骑在一种滑板上，对吧？
Yeah, basically it's a big skateboard and you lie down on it, your feet go down and
对，基本上就是一个大滑板，你躺在上面，脚朝下，
your head is back.
头朝后。
You're on your back and you go downhill really fast.
你仰面躺着，然后快速冲下山坡。
This is actually an Olympic sport and it's simply called luge and you can see this with
这其实是一项奥运项目，就叫雪橇，你可以看到那些
those big icy tracks that they have and they go downhill and they slide down on a bob sled
大冰道上，他们冲下山坡，坐在雪橇上滑下去，
or luge would actually be the same thing but just one or two people on some type of like
或者雪橇其实是一样的东西，只是一两个人坐在某种像
skateboard looking thing.
滑板一样的东西上。
Basically it's open.
基本上是敞开的。
The bob sled is closed so you see the people's heads but the luge you just see their whole
雪橇是封闭的，所以你只能看到人的头，但雪橇你能看到他们整个
body and they're lying down on a piece of metal and they go down very, very quickly.
身体，他们躺在一块金属上，非常非常快地滑下去。
They go very fast.
他们速度很快。
I think in bob sledding and luge, I think they can reach speeds up to like 100 kilometers
我觉得在雪橇和雪橇运动中，他们能达到每小时100公里
per hour or more.
或更快的速度。
That's right.
没错。
And this year it was actually very sad at the Olympics.
今年奥运会上其实发生了一件很悲伤的事。
A luge, I think it was luge athlete died in practice.
一个雪橇运动员，我想是雪橇运动员，在训练中去世了。
That's right.
没错。
So extreme sports or adventure sports, they are as the name says full of adventure, very
所以极限运动或冒险运动，正如其名，充满冒险，非常
exciting but also obviously very dangerous.
刺激，但显然也很危险。
I think hiking is not really an adventure sport or very dangerous unless you're hiking
我觉得徒步旅行不算冒险运动或很危险，除非你在有熊之类的危险地带
in dangerous territory with bears or something.
徒步。
Possible.
有可能。
Well, maybe you guys should let us know what kind of sports do you do.
嗯，也许你们应该告诉我们你们做什么运动。
Do you enjoy adventure sports?
你们喜欢冒险运动吗？
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Alright.
好的。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Thanks for heading out.
谢谢收听。